Sara Carvalho

sararfcarvalho.github.io

sararfcarvalho@gmail.com

+351 926 896 554

For over 7 years, I have dedicated myself to enhancing user experiences in the digital world, making it more accessible and user-friendly for people. I have worked as a UI developer for 4 years before transitioning to UX Design, where I have been honing my skills for an additional 3 years.

Experience

Talkdesk - Product Designer

May 2022 - now

- Solving problems analyzing user pain points and develop innovative solutions
- Conducting user research user interviews and user testing to gain deep insights into user behavior, preferences, and motivations.
- Analyzing user data to improve usability, find opportunities and make informed design decisions
- Presenting new ideas and reports to key stakeholders
- · Creating wireframes taking into consideration user and business needs
- Making prototypes that provide a comprehensive vision for the final product
- Designing user-friendly and user-centred mockups
- Identifying and troubleshooting UX problems
- Leading innovative workshops and brainstorming sessions to encourage team creativity, foster collaborative problem-solving leading to breakthrough product concepts.

Critical Software - User Experience Designer

February 2020 - April 2022

- Worked in a cross-functional product team following agile principles
- Designed interface elements with best practices in mind and applying UX principles
- Developed the design system and component libraries to enhance design consistency, scalability, and usability of the product.

4por4 Creative Agency - Frontend Developer

April 2017 - January 2020

 Developed fully functional and visually appealing websites with HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

4por4 Creative Agency - Web Designer Intern

July 2016 - March 2017

- Created website mockups
- Website development with CSS and HTML

GEN - Frontend developer Intern

March 2016 - June 2016

Education

EDIT - UI UX Design Course

2018 - 2019

UTAD - Communication & Multimedia Master Degree

2014 - 2017

UTAD - Communication & Multimedia Bachelor Degree

2011 - 2014

Skills

Figma, Sketch, InVision, Adobe Illustrator, Miro, Dovetail HTML, CSS

